译者:微博@Emtee
私人采购员
楼上用小钥匙
So, um, the little key is for the lock up top.
楼下用大钥匙
And the one for below.
你不留宿?
You're not staying?
我可不想 有太多回忆了
No, I prefer not to. Too many memories.
你不介意吧
It's good for you?
当然不介意 我理解
Yeah, of course. I understand.
- 再见 - 好的
- See you later. - Okay.
刘易斯?
Lewis?
刘易斯 是你吗
Lewis, is that you?
刘易斯
Lewis!
茉琳
Maureen?
我不知道我睡着了
I don't know...  I fell asleep.
怎么说
So?
有个存在体
There was a presence.
我感觉到了什么 我只是...
I felt something. I just can't...
讲不清 它太远了
I can't tell, it was too far.
你必须建立联系
You must make contact.
我觉得这可能需要我们两个才能做到
I think there might need to be two of us for that.
还不够吸引它
There... There wasn't enough pull.
因为我感觉到了什么 而它在保持距离
Because I felt something. It was just keeping its distance.
来
Come here.
看见十字印没
You see the cross?
看见了
Yeah.
是一直在那的吗
Has that always been there?
她说她没法建立联系
She said that she couldn't make a contact.
她还是感觉有存在体吗
Does she still feel a presence?
是啊 她说房子被占据了
Yes, she says the house is inhabited.
我们要确定了才能买
Well, we can't buy unless we're sure.
我们得知道它善不善良
We need to know if it's benevolent or not.
这投入太多了
It's too much of an investment.
嘿 那里...
Hey... um... So, there...
可能什么人都没
Could be no one.
但可能有别的什么 我需要更多时间
But there could be something. I-I just need more time, I think.
找到灵界入口是极为困难的
It's extremely difficult to find a portal into the spiritual world.
这种事就是这样
It's the way that it is.
我上周在斯德哥尔摩
I was in Stockholm last week,
我在现代艺术博物馆看了一场精彩的展览
I saw a wonderful exhibition at the Modern Art Museum.
希尔玛·阿夫·克林特
Hilma af Klint.
你听说过她吗
Have you ever heard of her?
没有
No.
她说 灵托她作画
She says that spirits commission her paintings.
她在1906年 先于康定斯基和马列维奇
She invented abstract art before Kandinsky and Malevitch
创造了抽象艺术
in 1906.
她宣称
She claims that
灵界是通过她来与我们交流的
the spirit-world communicated with us through her.
希尔玛·阿夫·克林特
抽象
先驱
发现希尔玛·阿夫·克林特的作品时 让我着迷的是
What fascinated me when I discovered Hilma af Klint's work was...
这些被画于1900年代早期的
That these grand and enigmatic paintings
宏大的神秘之作
had been painted in the early 1900's.
它们出自一位我从未听过的
And that they were made by a Swedish female artist
瑞典女艺术家之手
that I hadn't heard about before.
最让人着迷的地方或许在于
Maybe the most fascinating part is that these pieces
这些作品被画于抽象艺术概念出现之前
were made before the conception of abstract art.
但希尔玛·阿夫·克林特对她的艺术做了保密处理
But Hilma af Klint kept her art secret,
她确信它们在她有生之年不会被理解
She was sure that they wouldn't be understood during her life.
她在遗嘱中决定
In her will she decided that they would
等她逝世20年后 再将它们初展
be kept hidden until 20 years after her death.
百年前 希尔玛·阿夫·克林特
So, a century ago, Hilma af Klint
给未来作画
painted for the future.
而如今 未来已至
And the future is here now.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
在接待区不觉得太无聊吗
It didn't bore you too much at reception?
不觉得 习惯了 我的护照丢了
No, no more than normal. I lost my passport.
- 她在米兰待多久 - 两天
- How long will she be in Milan for? - Two days.
我把所有东西都挂架子上了
I put everything on a rack.
有来自新成衣系列的皮裤
Here are the leather pants from the new collection.
这些是琪拉的风格 我看得出很适合她
They're Kyra's style. I mean, I can see her in them.
能剪裁吗 有这可能吗 太大了
Are we able to cut them? Is it possible? They'll be too big.
我拿去看看
Let me look into this.
我要去厂家帮你拿
I'll get them for you from the studio.
我真不该这么做 但...
I'm not really supposed to, but...
请你尽快还回来
Please, you bring them back as soon as you can,
不然我会有麻烦
otherwise I will be in big trouble.
好的
Of course.
她需要更显眼点的 出席美国艾滋病研究基金会晚宴
She's going to need something a little flashier for the Amfar dinner.
好的
Yeah.
这些是刘易斯挑出来用于晚宴的
That's the stuff Lewis set aside for the dinner.
刘易斯喜欢的话 她也会喜欢
If Lewis likes it, then she'll love it.
- 你喜欢这件?  - 嗯
- You like it? - Mm.
刘易斯也喜欢 这件很挑人
So does Lewis. It's not easy to wear.
性感而又刚毅
It's sensual and strong.
要这件了 还要靴子
I'll take it, and some boots.
好的
Okay.
那两个包和这根皮带 我要了
I think I'll take both bags and this belt.
你知道她的 我不想冒险
You know her. I don't wanna risk it.
琪拉肯定想要棕色的
Kyra would want the brown, for sure.
或者蓝色的 或者都不要
Or the blue. Or neither.
她给了我张空白支票
Ah, she gave me a blank check.
- 你收押金吗 - 收的
- Do... do you take deposits? - Yes.
- 4500 - 好的
- 4,500. - Cool.
皮带500 包2000一个
500 for the belt, and 2,000 for each bag.
好的
Great.
茉琳 我回来过了 但我得赶时间
Maureen, I got back but I have to leave right away.
我们见不着面了 我明早去米兰
We'll miss each other. I'm off to Milan tomorrow morning.
我留了个信封 里面有过去两周欠你的钱
I'm leaving an envelope with what I owe you for the last two weeks.
保重 琪拉留
Take care. Kyra.
附 我把苹果电脑留桌上了
PS: I left my Mac on the desk.
你能帮我升级吗
Can you do the upgrade for me?
盖瑞来电
希尔玛·阿夫·克林特进入了唯灵论者的圈子
Hilma af Klint has moved in spiritual circles
并参与了降神会
and participated in seances,
后来她也成了灵媒
later she was also a medium.
唯灵论的本质到底是什么
What actually is regarded as the essence of spiritualism?
唯灵论的中心思想是
Well, the central idea of spiritualism,
我们世界之外有着另一个世界
is the idea that there is a world beyond our world.
唯灵论者试图给这个世界提供实践证据
And spiritualists try to give empirical proof for this world.
1848年
In 1848,
福克斯姐妹听到了敲击声
the Fox sisters heard rappings
她们把这些敲击声诠释为 是已故之人传达的信息
and they interpreted these rappings as messages from deceased persons.
对她们来说 这是真正意义上的证据
And that was for them real proof
证明了我们的世界之外有着更高级的世界存在
for the existence of a higher world beyond our world.
有趣的是 莫尔斯电码的发明比这早两年
It's interesting that the Moriset code had been invented 2 years earlier.
唯灵论者总是很了解先进科技
The spiritualists were always very close to the technological avant-garde.
比如 第一张抽象照片
For example, the first abstract photographs
是由唯灵论者们拍的
have been taken by spiritualists.
希尔玛·阿夫·克林特相信 她的抽象画作
Hilma af Klint believed that she received the abstract paintings
领受于更高级的意识
from higher levels of consciousness.
当她开始作为灵媒作画时
When she started to paint as a medium,
她摒弃了她在美术学院学得的画技
she rejected the skills she had learned at the art academy.
这是由于唯灵论和神智学的影响
And that was due to the influence of spiritualism and theosophy.
你提到了神智学
Now you mentioned theosophy,
鲁道夫·施泰纳是怎么看待抽象艺术的
What was Rudolf Steiner's view on abstract art?
施泰纳排斥抽象画作
Steiner rejected abstract paintings.
但实际情况更复杂 有很多...
But that's not the whole story.A lot of...
嘿
Hey.
我一个礼拜都在联系你
I've been trying to reach you for a week.
我知道 我一直在工作
I know. I've been working.
很忙
A lot.
抱歉
Sorry.
和琪拉怎么样
How's it going with Kyra?
就没见到过她
Ah... I never see her.
我们互相留言
We leave each other messages.
我其实讨厌这份工作
I hate this job, actually.
我真他妈讨厌她 她是个...
I fucking hate her. She's a...
你以前不是这么说的
That's not what you said before.
以前待在巴黎 付付房租 就很开心
Yeah I was just happy to stay in Paris and pay my rent.
哪变了呢
Yeah, well, what's changed?
时间都用在一堆破事上
I spend my days doing bullshit.
我不喜欢 可又做不了感兴趣的
That doesn't interest me, and it keeps me from what does.
我快他妈疯了
It's driving me fucking crazy.
你应该来这里
You should come here.
去阿曼苏丹国?
Yeah, to the Sultanate of Oman?
我还要在这待两个月
I'll be here another two months.
我还以为你快完工了
I thought you were almost done?
我重配了大使馆的电脑系统
I finished reconfiguring the embassy's computer system
现在在等安全协议
and now I'm just waiting for the security protocols.
你觉得你什么时候能拿到
When do you think you'll get those?
可能明天 也可能下个月
It could be tomorrow, could be next month...
我一拿到 就开始安装 配置
And once I get them I start the installing and configure them.
来马斯喀特吧
Come to Muscat!
看 我来海边过周末了
Look, I came to the seaside for the weekend.
很美
It's beautiful.
我去马斯喀特做什么呢
What the hell would I do in Muscat?
做你在巴黎做的事
What the hell you do in Paris?
你知道...
You know...
我在等 我得等着
I'm waiting. I have to wait.
已经三个月了
It's been three months.
我觉得我感觉到了什么
I think I felt something.
我得回刘易斯家 我真觉得我感觉到了什么
I need to go back to Lewis' house. I really think I felt something.
你觉得你感觉到了什么 你确定吗
You think you felt something or you're sure?
我得彻底搞清楚 就是这样
I just need to see it to the end. That's all.
这件很完美 要这件 谢谢
This is perfect. This works. Thank you.
还有这件
This too.
我看看这件
I see this...
这件其实会很完美
Actually it may be perfect.
我想你穿上看看
I'd like to see them on you.
你不想穿上试试吗
You don't want to try them on?
你了解她的 我不能穿
I... you know her. I can't.
但你想穿
But you want to.
没错 要是你不说出去 我或许会穿
Sure, I mean.. if you could keep your mouth shut, maybe...
但我上次穿了 你就出卖了我
but you totally dicked me over the last time I did it.
至少试下鞋子吧 我去拿
Try on the shoes at least. I'll get them.
和你的尺码一样 她不会把它们送回来的
They're the same size. She won't have to send them back.
好吧 维森特
Okay, Vincent...
你必须向我保证
You have to promise me...
一个字都不能说
Not one word. Not one word.
我的嘴已经封住了
My lips are sealed.
真的?
Really?
有车必有堵 你也没办法
If there's traffic, there's traffic. Nothing you can do about it.
他们会等
They'll wait.
他们正好需要点日光 没事
They just need a little daylight. It's okay.
不行 我等不了 我有事
No, I can't wait. I have an appointment.
下午在你家碰面吧
I'll meet you at your place later this afternoon?
好的
Okay.
皮裤都很棒吧
The leather pants. They're great, right?
这些不行 你不能留着 我保证过...
No, not these..you can't keep... I promised...
我保证过要在早上带回去
I promised that I'd bring them back in the morning.
请别这样
Please don't do that to me.
我就去跟他们讲 没事的 别担心 好的
I'm telling them right now. It's no problems. Don't worry. Okay.
嘿 她在路上 要晚到 从米兰过来的飞机晚点了
Hey so, she is on her way. She's late. Her plane from Milan was just delayed.
但她在哪呢
But where is she?
她在高速公路上 显然堵车了
She's on a highway. There's traffic, apparently.
你能代替她吗 节省时间
Can you stand in for her? It'll save some time.
我四点必须走
I have to leave at four o'clock.
没问题 太好了 来吧
Yeah, that's okay. It's perfect. Come.
你觉得她会全都改掉?
You think she'll ditch everything?
没错 她会全都改掉 不过我给了你三个选择 你应该...
Yeah, she'll ditch everything. I brought you three options though.You should...
那样就能通过了吗
With that we'll make it through?
我保证不了
I can't make any promises.
你待着我会更自在
I'd feel more comfortable if you stayed.
你怕琪拉?
You scared of Kyra?
我听说她是个怪物
I hear she's a monster.
这是你的左心室
This is your left ventricle.
只是稍微大了点
It's just slightly larger in size.
和你胞胎哥哥的完全一样
It was exactly the same for your twin brother.
你不会有事 能活到100岁
You can live with it and die at 100.
或是27岁?
Or at 27?
我诊疗刘易斯和我诊疗你一样
I treated Lewis just like I treated you.
每年两次超声波检查
An ultrasound twice a year.
没有过迹象 什么都没
There was no sign. Nothing.
有一天 它就停下了
One day, it just gave way.
别害怕 茉琳 刘易斯的事是特例
Don't be scared, Maureen. What happened to Lewis is very exceptional.
譯禇 嶶ъο Ｅмτèè
你能起身了
You can get up.
一切正常
Everything is fine.
你只需要避免剧烈的身体活动
You just need to keep avoiding both intense physical efforts
和过激情绪
and extreme emotions.
就像刘易斯那样
Like Lewis did...
- 我意思是 他做了些柜子  - 我知道
- I mean,... he built cabinets. - I know.
他想把房子弄成工作室
He wanted to turn the house into a studio
用来教授和练习木工
where he could teach and practice carpentry.
他真的认为那是他的未来
He really considered it his future.
六个月后我们再见吧
I'll see you again in six months?
我不知道六个月后我会怎么样
I have no idea where I'm going to be in six months.
晚上好 茉琳
Good evening, Maureen.
不好意思 我们没见过面
Excuse me, we haven't met.
我叫英戈
I'm Ingo.
你好 不好意思
Hi! Um, sorry...
琪拉在吗
Is Kyra here?
和她的律师一起在她房里
In her room with her lawyer.
在进行电话会议 已经一个小时了
They've been on a conference call for an hour.
和基金会有问题
Problems with the foundation.
我来拿几样东西 她知道的
I'm just here to pick up a few things. She's aware.
你知道在哪吗
Do you know where they are?
那里有个衣物袋
There is one garment bag over there.
随口问下
Um, random question, but
你知道两条皮裤在哪吗
do you happen to know about two pairs of leather pants?
应该在袋里的
They should be in the bag.
她想留着
She wants to keep them.
好吧
Okay.
她在那里面?
She's just in there?
她真的很让人讨厌 对吧
Ah, she's a real fucking pain-in-the-ass, right?
我们为此努力了六个月
We've been working on this for six months.
我们不能在最后一刻取消媒体采访
We can't just call off the press trip at the last minute.
嘿 琪拉
Hey Kyra?
我们有头两岁的大猩猩 失踪三周了
We have a 2-year-old gorilla who's been gone for three weeks.
而现在这一家子都出问题了
And now we have a problem with the whole family.
盖尔曼夫人的丈夫为大猩猩栖息地的保护
Mrs. Gellman's husband invests a lot of time and money
投入了大量时间和金钱
into gorilla habitat preservation.
他非常关心大猩猩
He cares deeply about gorillas.
但如果出了岔子
But if things go wrong,
就会严重影响他的商业利益
this reflects really badly on his business interests...
嘿 琪拉 我能小问下吗
Hey Kyra, can I just ask you one word quick question?
这很严重 你得处理好
This is serious. You need to take care of this.
在吗
Hello?
母猩猩很抑郁
The female is depressive.
公猩猩 纳加博 你熟的 变得很有攻击性
The male, Ngabo, you're familiar with him is becoming aggressive.
纳加博在有压力的情况下 会变得非常有攻击性
Ngabo can become very aggressive in stressful situations.
我记得非常清楚 谢谢
I remember very well, thank you.
它们现在在哪 大猩猩们在哪
Where are they now? Where are the gorillas?
它们走得越来越深入山里了
They wander off further and further into the mountain
很难监控它们
and it's difficult to monitor them.
我们不能取消记者采访
We can't cancel the reporters!
我们有合同义务 我们需要看到那些大猩猩
We have contractual obligations. We need those gorillas to be there.
就小问下
Just one quick question?
我听到的都是问题 而不是解决方案
I'm hearing problems, I'm not hearing solutions.
介意我抽烟吗
Mind if I smoke?
你除了给琪拉配装 没别的事做了吗
You have nothing better to do besides dress Kyra?
觉得很有意义吗
Really find it worthy of your time?
你有更好的职务提供吗
Do you have a better offer?
没有
Not exactly.
我是时尚男士版的柏林通讯员
I'm a correspondent for Men's Vogue in Berlin.
我能帮你说说
I can put in a word for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
但杂志不适合我
But I..you know, magazines aren't really my thing.
都是狗屁
They sell shit.
主要面向广告客户 而不是读者
Mainly for advertisers, rather than readers.
那又怎么样 你已经干了份蠢工作
So what? You already have a stupid job.
这点上不会有任何变化
It wouldn't change a thing but,
然而薪水更多
it pays better.
不适合我
Not for me.
一些备受推崇的摄影师会在时尚杂志上刊登作品
Some highly-regarded photographers publish in fashion magazines.
免费?
Are they free?
我想是的
I suppose so.
是吗
Yeah?
他们能选择拍摄品牌和对象?
They get to choose their brands and subjects they shoot?
当然不能
No, that's correct.
我真不觉得这有自由可言
I don't really see the freedom in that.
好了 我要走了
Yeah, I'm going to go.
衣服和包我拿走了
I'll take the dress and the bags.
你得告诉她 她得还裤子
You really need to tell her she's gotta return those pants.
我明天再来
I'll come back tomorrow.
她明天在这吗
Do you know she'll be here tomorrow?
你问她
Ask her.
她会叫我走人
She'll tell me to leave.
你不会走?
And you're not leaving?
我在等她开完会 我想跟她谈话
I'm waiting for her to finish. I want to speak with her.
她想甩了我
She wants to dump me.
你们多久了
How long's it been?
两年
Two years.
但她怕她丈夫发现
But she's scared her husband will find out.
我肯定他有所怀疑了
I'm sure he suspects something.
你爱上了她?
You in love with her?
爱?
Love?
没有 我从没有过这感觉
It never crossed my mind, no.
只是肉体上的
It's just physical.
你来巴黎做什么
What are you doing in Paris?
我在等待
I'm... waiting.
我要走了
I'm gonna go.
你在等待什么
What are you waiting for?
我哥哥死在这里
My... uh... brother died here.
我的胞胎哥哥
My twin brother,
死在巴黎
died in Paris.
事故?
An accident?
不是
No.
心脏病
A heart attack.
实际上 我有相同的
I actually have the same...
先天畸形
malformation.
你怕吗
Does it scare you?
不怕
No.
他也不怕
And it didn't scare him.
你待在这里哀悼他
You stay here to mourn.
不是 我在等待
No, I'm waiting.
我跟你说了我在等待
I told you I was waiting.
你在等待什么
What are you waiting for?
我们立过一个誓约
So, we made this oath.
不管谁先死  都要给另一个示以迹象
Whoever died first would send the other a sign.
迹象?
A sign?
从阴世?
From the afterlife?
你可以这么称呼 怎么称呼都行
You could call it that. You could call it a million things.
但你要怎么知道是不是迹象
But how will you know if it's a sign?
我是个灵媒
I'm a medium.
他也曾是灵媒
He was a medium.
我就是会知道
I'll just know it.
你以前和灵交流过吗
Have you communicated with spirits before?
刘易斯认为有灵存在 我不太确定
Lewis thought there were... spirits. I'm less sure.
但...我交流过
But... y-yes.
某种程度上交流过
Somewhat.
我们身边一直都
There are invisible presences...
有着看不见的存在体
around us, always.
无论是不是死人的魂 但...
Whether or not they're the souls of the dead, I don't know, but...
你成了灵媒 就会灵敏地感觉到某种...
When you're a medium, you just are attuned to a sort of...
气场
vibe.
你说的气场是什么意思
What do you mean by vibe?
这是种直觉感知的东西 感觉就像...
It's an intuition thing. It's a feeling you...
你看到一扇门
You see this door...
它只开了一点点
It's only like slightly ajar.
我还认为
I also think that...
魂
the soul...
在人死后会继续存在
continues to exist after death.
我真不知道我信不信
I don't really know if I believe in that.
但刘易斯信
But Lewis did.
我必须给他的灵...
And I have to give his spirit...
随你怎么称呼它
whatever you want to call it...
一个机会来证明他是对的
a chance to prove him right.
直到什么时候
Until when?
我得到过一个迹象
I had a sign.
- 哦? - 没错
- Oh? - Yeah!
你确定吗
Are you sure?
不确定 所以我仍在等待
No. That's why I'm still waiting.
然后?
And then?
然后我想我会过我的生活
Then I guess I'll live my life.
让自己放下
Let it go.
我早上来找你
I'll come for you in the morning.
- 或更早些 有事就打我电话 - 好的
- Or before. Call when you want. - Okay.
嘿
Hey.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们考虑过了 我们要翻新
So we thought about it, and we're renovating.
我觉得这是刘易斯想做的
I think that's what Lewis would have wanted.
我只希望茉琳在这地方 有了刘易斯的灵陪伴
I just wanted Maureen to be at peace with this place.
能变得安宁
And with Lewis' spirit.
我只是想说
I... I just wanted to say one last...
刘易斯会很高兴这房子又是你们的了
Lewis would have been very happy that this house is yours again...
我也很高兴
And I'm very glad too.
现在这是你们的房子
Now, it's your house and...
我会把它忘掉
I'll forget it.
来吧
Come on.
我需要你给我更多
I need more from you.
我会需要你给我更多
I'm gonna need more from you.
再给我一个迹象
Give me one more sign.
什么都行
Anything.
给我最微小的迹象
Give me the tiniest thing.
就这样吗
Is that it? Is that it?
最微小的迹象就好
Just the tiniest little thing...
你能看到我 但没法跟我说话 是吗
Is it that you can see me, you cannot talk to me?
刘易斯 我他妈不要你对水管做什么
Lewis,I don't care what you do with the fucking plumbing.
我要你跟我说话
I need you to fucking talk to me!
求你了 我不明白
Please, I don't understand.
你不是我哥哥
You're not my brother.
未知号码 我认识你
你也认识我
你要去伦敦
你是谁
猜猜看
不猜 回答我的问题
你是男是女
这有什么关系吗
你是真实的吗
你是活人还是死人
是活人还是死人
刘易斯?
飞行模式
开启
飞行模式 关闭
我想要你
别发了
我想要你 我会得到你
你怎么弄到这个号码的
我要屏蔽你了
你不再想知道我是谁了?
我在这里 我看着你
我开玩笑的 我不在那
但我可能在伦敦
你想知道我在哪?
在哪
谢谢回复
我不会在伦敦
你放心了?
还是失望了?
你想要什么
你
不是肉体上的
想先
建立联系
琪拉要的我都准备好了
I've prepared everything Kyra asked for.
两件她从照片里选的礼服
Two dresses she picked from the photograph,
还一件被拍得不是很好 但我觉得她会喜欢
and a third one that didn't photograph so well but I think she'll like it.
哪一件
Which one?
这一件
This one there.
是丝质透明硬纱
It's silk organza.
在照片里会失去些光泽 但是
In a photo you lose some of the sheen but,
有光就真的很好看
It really plays well with the light.
没错 很棒
Oh yeah, it's cool.
真的很棒
It's really cool.
背带也有不同的颜色譯禇 覹愽 Emtёё
The harness comes in different colours as well.
- 我可以看看吗 - 可以
- Can I see them? - Yeah.
给 有金色 黑色 和裸色
There you go. We've got gold, black and nude.
要黑色
In black.
不是所有人都会喜欢 但我觉得琪拉穿上会很好看
Not for all tastes, but I think it'll look amazing with Kyra.
你想试试吗
Do you want to try it?
来吧
Come.
我提议玩个游戏
我讨厌游戏
不好意思
Sorry.
你想试试礼服吗
You want to try the dress?
不了 我要两种颜色 让她可以选择
No, I'll take it in two colours so that she has the option.
好的 我会都包装好给你
Cool. I'll get it all packed up for you.
那就不玩游戏 搞别的
什么意思
你在等火车吗
没错
回答我的问题
你想成为别人吗
想
谁
我不知道
我没法帮你知道
告诉我让你感到不安的东西
恐怖片
为什么
有杀手 女人要逃命 要躲藏
让你感到不安的是恐惧
你经常感到害怕吗
不会
未知号码
我在火车上 稍等
I'm on the train.Give me one second.
今晚我会把东西带过去
I'll drop the stuff off this evening.
你什么时候回去
When do you get back?
就算是下午早些时候 那...
Even if it's early afternoon,it's...
那也没关系 我会帮你放在衣物袋里
It's okay. It'll be ready for you in a garment bag.τгаηslаτed ьγ ωeiьо-Eмτee
我得从卡地亚拿首饰
I have to pick up the jewellery from Cartier,
但他们说都准备好了
but everything, they said, is ready.
可以的话 我更想要欧元
I would prefer it in euros if that's not a problem...
你从戴高乐机场回去的路上 能叫司机开到自动取款机那
You know you could ask your driver to stop at an ATM on the way back from CDG.
两秒就好
It'll take two seconds.
It was 400.
没错 谈的是400
Yeah.We agreed on 400.
还有几张出租车票据
There are a couple of taxi receipts as well.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
昨天我试穿了雇我工作的那女人的鞋子
你为什么告诉我
因为她不会让我试穿
所以答案是禁忌的事?
百无禁忌就无欲无求
还有什么是禁忌的
回答我的问题?
是的
你回来了吗
回来了
你家?
琪拉家?
你怎么知道
你想试试琪拉的礼服?
是的
因为是禁忌的?
琪拉·盖尔曼 美国艾滋病研究基金会 米兰时装周
译{}者{}:{}微{}博{}@{}E{}m{}t{}e{}e
我穿了
你害怕了
是的
我以为你想成为别人
茉琳
圣拉扎尔康科德酒店 下午4点 724号房
你怎么样
How are you?
你确定那个灵不在那了?
You're sure the spirit isn't there anymore?
是的
Yes.
她吐出了灵质
She vomited this ectoplasm
然后离开了
and left.
灵质存留了一分钟
And the ectoplasm lingered for a minute,
或更短 然后也消失了
or less and then also disappeared.
你知道她想要什么吗
Do you have an idea of what she wanted?
她很愤怒 很暴力
She was really angry. Very violent.
或许她想算账
Maybe she had a score to settle.
我觉得她迷失了
I think she was lost.
我觉得她并不想回来 我觉得她不会再去那
I don't think she wants to come back. I don't think she'll be there again.
刘易斯呢
And what about Lewis?
已经95天了
It's been 95 days.
杰罗姆和卡桑德拉买下了房子
Jérôme and Cassandre are getting the bigger house.
很好
Good.
刘易斯真的很喜欢他们 所以...
You know, Lewis really loved them so that's...
太好了
perfect.
你呢
What about you?
打算怎么用那些钱
What'll you do with the money?
不用
Nothing.
我不知道
I don't know.
我不知道我能买什么
I'm not sure I can buy something else.
我对未来没有足够的信心
I'm not confident enough about the future.
我懂
I feel you.
我不觉得你理解
I don't think you understand.
我绝对理解 相信我
I definitely understand. Trust me.
我遇到了一个人
I met someone.
你遇到了一个... 就像...
You met some...like you...
听着
Look,
你肯定早就认识他了
You must've known him before.
算是吧
Well, kind of...
一个朋友的朋友
A friend of a friend.
刘易斯死后 他来联系我
After Lewis died, he reached out to me,
我们发展得很亲近
and we grew closer.
你很惊讶
You're shocked.
没有 这很好 我没...
No. Good. I wasn't...
这是我没想到的 不过 当然了
I wasn't expecting it but like, of course.
我会永远爱刘易斯
I'll always love Lewis,
但我不能在哀悼中度过一生
but I can't spend my life in mourning.
我不喜欢哀悼
I'm not interested in mourning,
我已经承受过够多的痛苦了
Like suffering in pain, I've had enough.
我觉得我现在想好好过日子
I think now I want life.
有一天 你说过
The other day, you said
维克多·雨果 你说他和灵交流过
Victor Hugo actu... you know, you said that he communicated with spirits...
什么意思 是真的跟它们说话?
What did you mean by that? Like actually talked to them?
是的
Yeah.
他流亡泽西岛时  扭转了处境
When he was exiled in Jersey, he turned tables.
他与著名的历史人物交谈
Like he conversed with famous historical figures like,
甚至包括圣经人物
even biblical ones.
那里很漂亮
It's pretty out there.
怎么交谈的
How?
我真不知道
I don't really know.
我意思是口头说还是用字母
I mean literally. Like verbally or with an alphabet?
不是用字母 他们试过 但灵拒绝了
No, no, not the alphabet. They tried, but the spirit refused.
那他怎么做的
So what did he do?
用柱脚桌
With a pedestal table.
柱脚会敲击地板 一次表示肯定  两次表示否定
The leg would tap on the floor like, once for "yes", twice for "no".
或者一次表示A 两次表示B 以此类推
Like one for "A", two for "B" and so on like,
26次表示Z
26 for "Z".
这要花的时间 多得惊人
That would take an unbelievable amount of time.
是的 手录稿不计其数
Yeah. There were pages and pages of transcriptions.
一定都是瞎扯的
Well, that's gotta be bullshit.
- 那是编造的 - 不是
- That's invented. - Ah, no, no, no.
- 这绝不可能 - 没有 他是真的相信
- There's no way that happened. - No he really believed it.
又不是用于出版 为什么要编造
It was not intended for publication. So, why invent it?
我认为不管是谁手录
I think whoever did the transcripts
肯定都会详略结合 填补期间空档
must have adapted them, filled in the gaps.
所以有点像速记?
So, like stenography? Kind of.
没错 类比得不错
Yeah, that's a good analogy.
不过你感兴趣的话
But if you're interested,
有部60年代的电视电影描述了那里的降神会
there's a TV movie from the sixties that depicts the seance.
片子很糟 但似乎是准确再现
It's really tacky, but seems accurate.
我能帮你找下片名 不过你在Youtube上
I'll find the title for you, but if you type in like:
输入 雨果+泽西岛+灵动桌 就能找到了
"Hugo+Jersey+Turning Tables" on YouTube, you will find it.
你是疯狗吗
Crazy dog, aren't you?
在泽西岛的维克多·雨果
一个被称为白衣女士的生物在第一天问了我一件我做过的事
The being called the white lady asked me on the first day a thing that I did.
我知道这样的生物 不敢来 会跑开
I know that a being, afraid of coming, ran away.
有谁在这里吗
Is there someone here?
敲一下表示肯定
If yes knock once...
敲两下表示否定
If no knock twice.
在我问你是谁之前 我先问你个问题
Before I ask you who you are, I'll ask you a question.
但你能从我的脑海中得知这个问题吗
But first, this question, do you see it in my thoughts?
你想回答吗
Do you want to answer it?
那说吧
Then talk.
山是我的坟墓
The mountain is my grave.
我是神的吐息 我上天下地 我想要天空 而大地想要我
I'm God's breath, I go up and down, I want the sky and the Earth wants me.
群星拉着我的头发 棺材钉固定着我的脚
The stars pull me by my hair and the nails of the coffin hold me by my feet.
黑暗朝我大喊 下来 太阳对我说 上来
The darkness screams to me: "Down!" And the Sun says "Up!" to me.
我是不安的地平线
I'm the uncomforted of the horizon.
我是无数坟墓的守夜人
I'm the night watcher of countless graves,
清理空颅骨中的眼睛
emptying his eyes in empty skulls.
我是噩梦之源
I'm the cause of bad dreams.
圣拉扎尔康科德酒店 下午4点 724号房
发我张照片
我喜欢这样的你
我觉得可笑 那不是我
我为自己感到羞耻
我不知道我为什么过来
拿好钥匙 你还会来的
- 打扰一下  - 什么事
- Excuse me. - Yes?
我想知道724房是在谁的名下定的
I need to know what name was room 724 was booked under?
好的 稍等
Okay, just a second.
724...
是...
It was...
查到的是茉琳· 卡特莱特
Maureen Cartwright, I have.
不会的 我就是茉琳· 卡特莱特 谁付的房费
No, I'm Maureen Cartwright. Who paid for the room?
稍等
Just a sec.
抱歉 没有信用卡信息
I'm sorry, there is no credit card information.
是提前用现金支付的
Was paid in advance in cash.
你还记得是男是女吗
Do you remember if it was a man or a woman?
不知道 那时不是我当班
I don't know. I was not working at that moment.
你能问问你的同事吗 你知道...
Would you ask a colleague? Do you know...?
这是家大酒店
It's a big hotel.
我不确定我帮得了你
I'm not sure I can help you with that.
谢谢
Thank you.
这些是你选的五件东西
These are the five pieces of your selection.
特别是巴黎新浪潮系列的艺术桥
And particularly the "Pont des Arts" of the "Paris Nouvelle" collection.
由18克拉玫瑰金和细石制成
Made of 18 carat rose gold and fine stones.
很好 很完美
C'est bien. Yes, it's perfect.
项链 手链 戒指 还有手表
The necklace, the bracelet, the ring and the watch,
但不包括这个 我从没见过它
but excluding this. I've never seen that.
好的 我来着重介绍这四件东西
Okay. Let me focus on these four.
- 好的 - 我会帮你都准备好
- Okay. - I'll prepare everything for you then.
谢谢
Merci.
不客气
You're welcome.
这个是全新的 首次发布
And this one is brand new, first time released.
所以没人有
So nobody has it.
很好 这点很重要 谢谢
Oh, good. That's important. Thank you.
嘿 琪拉 你回来了?
Hey Kyra, you back?
抱歉 我进来了 我就放下袋子 好吗
Sorry, I let myself in. I'm just gonna drop these bags for you, okay?
天呐
Jesus.
嗨嘿 琪拉 你还好吗
Hey Kyra, you doing alright?
嘿
Hey?
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
我开车开了...
I drove for...
大概两分钟 才意识到我在做什么
2 minutes maybe before I realized what I was doing,
然后我就回去报警了
And I came back and called.
你为什么不早点报警
Why didn't you do it earlier?
我吓坏了
I-I-I... I freaked out.
我逃跑了
I-I-I ran away.
你逃避一个存在体?
You ran away from a presence?
公寓后方...
There was a light on in the...
有灯亮着 我听到了些声音
back of the apartment, I heard something.
你在盖尔曼夫人家做什么
What were you doing at Mrs. Gellman's?
放几个袋子
Dropping off a couple of bags.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我是个私人采购员
I'm a personal shopper.
她备受关注 没空做...
She was very high profile and couldn't...
平常的事
do normal things, didn't have time.
我算是在这方面为她做事
And I sort of assisted her in that.
你昨晚用了盖尔曼夫人的电脑
You used Mrs. Gellman's computer last night.
或许吧
Um, maybe.
今天早上又用了
And again this morning.
你登陆了Gmail查看你的邮件
You check your messages on Gmail.
我们有记录
We have the record.
那你干嘛问
So, why are you asking?
你在她家睡过吗
Did you sleep at her place?
睡过 我在她家睡过
Yes, I did. I slept at her place.
为什么
Why?
我不知道
Um, I don't know.
说实话 我从不那么做
To be honest, I never do that.
你为什么不想说
Why did you hide it?
傻了
A stupid reaction.
或许 或许我...
Maybe, maybe I was...
觉得有点羞耻
a little ashamed.
你知道她今天要回家吗
You knew she was coming home today?
知道 她从米兰回来
Yeah. She was coming back from Milan,
要去马拉喀什
and on her way to Marrakech.
我是带饰品给她
I was dropping off some accessories for her.
什么饰品
What accessories?
首饰
Jewellery.
什么首饰
What jewellery?
很贵的卡地亚首饰
Very expensive jewellery from Cartier.
你放那了吗
And you left it there?
放了 四个盒子 在两个袋子里
Yeah. In four cases in two bags.
你回去后它们还在吗
Were they still there when you went back?
我不知道 我没...
I-I-I don't know. I wasn't...
当时我没顾及首饰
I wasn't considering the jewellery at that point...
我没注意
I didn't notice.
我发你的消息 你告诉警察了吗
回答我
如果吵醒了你 那我很抱歉
Sorry, if I woke you up.
我刚在对一个...
I was just stress-testing...
新的安全协议进行压力测试
one of the new security protocols.
真他妈难配置
Really fucking hard to configure.
要花我一个月的时间
So, it's gonna take me a month.
最好的情况是这样
Best case.
我要来见你
I'm gonna come see you.
你放弃了吗
You giving up?
是的 不会出现
Yeah, it's not going to happen.
茉琳 这不是不会出现的问题
Maureen, it's not that it isn't going to happen,
而是根本不存在
it's that it doesn't exist.
人死后
After death,
什么都不会留下
there's nothing.
我知道
I- I know.
这没什么的
And it's not that big a deal.
你跟我说过你心存希望
You told me that you had a hope...
你很希望...
Like you really hoped that...
当然了
Of course I do.
但不行
But, no.
我不相信
I don't believe.
我再也不想待在这了
I don't want to be here anymore.
我再也不想待在巴黎了
I don't want to be in Paris anymore.
我想你
I miss you.
我也想你
I miss you too.
我要去山上几天
I'm actually heading up the mountains for a few days.
你想去就快来 然后去那跟我碰面
If you want to, you can come quickly and meet me there.
也许…
Maybe...
这得看警察怎么说
It really depends on what the police say.
得看旅行禁令有没被解除
If the travel ban's been lifted or not.
警察?
The police?
是的 琪拉被谋杀了 你没听说吗
Yeah, Kyra was murdered, you didn't hear that?
- 到处都报道了 - 什么
- It's everywhere. - What?
新闻上都是
All over the news.
- 是我发现她的 - 被谋杀?
- I found her. - Murdered?
是谁杀了她
Who murdered her?
我不知道
I don't know.
真的太可怕了
It was really horr... It was, ah...
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我不想说这个  太他妈可怕了
I can't talk about it. It was fucking horrible.
你要我晚点打过来吗
You want me to call you back later?
我会打给你的
I'll call you.
皇冠广场酒店 329号房 马上过去
我会再等一小时
我知道你在看我发的消息 快过去
我也会去
你的钥匙我有备用的
我在出租车上
我在你家楼下
下来
就现在
我正在上来
我在你门外的楼梯口了
皇冠广场酒店 329号房
- 你还好吗 - 挺好
- You okay? - Yeah.
- 他们...我能喝吗 - 当然
- They... Can I have some? - Yeah, sure.
他们逮捕了英戈 他...
They arrested Ingo, and he...
他坦白了一切
and he confessed to everything.
他们解除旅行禁令了吗
Did they lift the travel ban?
解除了 结案了
Yeah. The case is closed.
但你要作证?
But you'll testify?
是的 大概吧
Yes, yeah, probably.
你想来我家吗
Do you want to come to my place?
想 我感觉...
Yeah. I feel, um...
现在我一个人很害怕
I'm scared when I alone now.
你要去见盖瑞 对吗
You're going to see Gary, right?
是的
Yes, Yep.
你不久前就该去了
You should have gone a while ago.
我本该听你的
I should have listened to you.
走吧 我开车来的
Let's go, I have my car.
- 早 - 早
- Morning. - Morning.
你是刘易斯的妹妹?
You're Lewis' sister?
是的
I am.
我们在布勒学院相处过
We were together at l'École Boulle.
现在我在哥白林工厂工作
Now I work at the Gobelin workshops.
实际上 我很快就要走了
Actually, I should get going soon.
你应该留下来
You should stay.
如果可以的话
If you can.
-  我叫茉琳  - 我叫艾尔文
- Maureen. - Erwin.
- 很高兴认识你 - 很高兴认识你
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
我理解你可能接受不了
I understand that you might feel uncomfortable.
为什么
Why?
因为我很快地取代了
Because I've taken Lewis' place.
刘易斯的位置
So soon.
完全没有
Not at all.
你误会了
You're mistaken.
他活着时 劳拉和我之间完全没什么
While he was alive, there was nothing between Lara and me.
说真的 我没那么想过
It didn't cross my mind. Honestly.
你知道人们为什么说死人会守护活人吗
You know how they say, the dead watch over the living?
这问题我想过很多
I've thought about that a lot.
不只是因为刘易斯是个灵媒
Not just because Lewis was a medium.
我不知道那是什么意思
I don't know what that means.
对我来说 他是个对别人有很强直觉力的人
For me, he was someone deeply intuitive of others.
他理解未被言说的事物
He understood things that went unspoken.
是的
He did.
也许是因为他知道他要死了
Maybe because he knew he was going to die.
我意思是我觉得他看到了我看不到的东西
I mean I felt that he saw things which I didn't.
也许你也看到了
Maybe you do too.
他认为你有同样的天赋
He thought that you had the same gifts.
我不知道
I don't know.
我...
I, ah..
曾想追随他
Had a tendency to follow him.
他做事会想得很远
He took things quite far.
至少对我来说很远
Too far for me, at least.
我跟不上
I couldn't keep up.
我想说的是 有刘易斯在
All I mean is that with Lewis,
就好像没有什么是不可能的
nothing seems impossible.
许多宗教相信 魂徘徊一段时间后
Many religions believe that the soul wanders around for a while
才离开这个世界
before leaving this world.
他跟你谈过这个?
Did he speak to you about that?
他对此很确信
He was convinced of it.
几年前 妈妈死了
Years ago, Mum died,
他确信...
he was sure that...
她来看他了 是来跟他道别的
he was visited by her. That she came to say goodbye to him.
那像一场梦 但并不是 那非常真实
That it felt like a dream, but not, that it was very real.
他能闻到她的味道 他能很清楚地看到她
He could smell her, he could see her so clearly... you know?
你信吗
Do you believe that?
我信
Yeah, I do.
这和宗教无关 但我...
It's not a religion thing, but I...
我信
I do.
你认为刘易斯在这里吗
Do you think Lewis is here?
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
我感觉到了他的存在
I feel his presence.
他在这里
He's here.
这可能是你的愧疚之言
That might be your guilt talking.
你不必觉得愧疚
You don't need to feel guilty.
劳拉理应幸福
Lara deserves to be happy.
你也是
And you do too.
我想这么想 但...
I like to think so but...
有什么在阻止我
something is stopping me.
但愿跟我没关系
I hope it has nothing to do with me.
是没关系
No.
但你也得让自己从刘易斯的事中解脱出来
But you also have to free yourself of Lewis.
我希望他会让我解脱
Well, I wish he'd let me.
无论他在哪
Wherever he is,
他都不会禁止你那么做
he would never forbid it.
即使他不在了
And even if he's nowhere,
那也别忘了他的自由
hold onto the memory of his freedom.
付诸实际行动吧
Put it into practice.
我明白你的意思
I know what you mean.
我得走了
You know, I have to get going.
你会住几天吗
Will you be staying a few days?
就今晚 我明天走
Just tonight. I leave tomorrow.
- 那今晚再见  - 好的
- So, I'll see you tonight. - Okay.
待在外面
Stay outside.
真乖
Good dog.
怎么了
What happened?
玻璃杯碎了
A glass broke.
我以为你在外面
I thought you were outside.
艾尔文刚走
Erwin just left.
他肯定把它放在桌子边缘了
He must have left it on the edge of the table, or something.
但愿你一路上都挺好
I hope you had a good trip.
先休息下吧
Get some rest.
你的司机叫瑟林
Your driver is named Salim.
最好在天亮前出发
It's best to leave a little before daybreak.
有五个小时的车程
Count on a five hour ride.
别担心 一路上很安全 即便不是人来车往
Don't worry, the road is safe, even if it is not very busy.
东西能不带就别带 需要的我都有
Take the minimum. I have everything we need.
也就是说 东西不是很多
In other words, not much.
你没问题的话 我们就待上一周
If it's okay with you, we'll stay for a week.
这是斯巴达式的生活 你必须忍受
You'll have to be tolerant, it's spartan.
不过你跟我说过 这是你想要的
But you told me this is what you wanted.
米斯法老房子旅馆
哈吉?
Hajji?
刘易斯?
Lewis?
你在这吗
Are you here?
你一直在等我吗
Have you been waiting for me?
你平静吗
Are you at peace?
谢谢
Thank you.
你不平静吗
Are you not at peace?
你在耍我吗
Are you playing with me?
你有恶意吗
Do you mean harm?
我不认识你
I don't know you.
你是谁
Who are you?
刘易斯 是你吗
Lewis, is it you?
还是 只是我
Or is it just me?
译者:微博@Emtee